Something's wrong with Ben.
Primate is a horror, thriller film directed by Johannes Roberts.
Lucy, a college student, along with her friends, spend their vacation at her
family's home in Hawaii, which includes her pet chimpanzee, Ben.
However, when Ben contracts rabies after being bitten by a rabid animal, the group
must fight for their lives in order to avoid the now-violent chimp.
Lucy, played by Johnny Sequoyah.
Hannah, played by Jessica Alexander.
Adam, played by Troy Kotsur.
Kate, played by Victoria Wyant.
Erin, played by Gia Hunter.
Nick, played by Benjamin Cheng.
Primate is a 2025 American natural horror film directed by Johannes
Roberts, who also co-wrote the screenplay with Ernest Riera.
It stars Johnny Sequoyah, Jessica Alexander, and Troy Kotsur.
In the film, a tropical vacation goes awry when Ben, an adopted chimpanzee,
is bitten by a rabid animal and suddenly becomes violent.
Primate premiered at the Fantastic Fest on September 18, 2025, and was
released in theaters on January 9, 2026, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and has grossed $25.5
million worldwide, making it the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2026.
The film explores themes of hawaii, pet, animal attack, gore, monkey.
The tone is dark and intense.